Data driven approaches can be very useful
数据驱动法可以说相当有用
particularly when we have access to plenty of training data.
特别是当你有大量训练数据的时候
But in some ways purely data driven approaches are naïve since they rely
但是 有时候纯粹的数据驱动法会很愚蠢
solely on historical evidence to make predictions about likely future behavior.
因为它们仅仅只是依赖于历史的事实来进行有关未来可能行为的预测
Ideally, we would also like to include, in our predictions,
理想情况下 在我们的预测中 我们很可能会将其他东西考虑在内
all the insights we have about driver behavior,
包括所有我们已知的对司机行为的深入了解
physics, or vehicle dynamics.
以及物理学或者车辆动力学的知识
This is where model based approaches can help.
这时候 基于模型法就很有用了
The way these approaches typically work is as follows.
下面是这些方法的典型用法
For each object identify all the behaviors
首先 对于每个目标 识别在当前状况下
that object is likely to do in the current situation.
目标的下一步所有可能的行为
The behavior for a vehicle could be something like change lanes,
对机动车来说 行为可能是类似于变换车道
turn left and for a pedestrian,
左转避让行人等等
it could be cross the street on pedestrian crossing.
因为行人可能正在斑马线上横穿街道
For our intersection scenario,
而对于我们的交叉路口场景
the behaviors could be go straight,
车辆行为可能是 直接前行
turn left, turn right.
左转 或者右转
Whatever it is, it needs to be something that we can describe mathematically.
无论行为是什么 我们都需要用数学方式把它们描述出来
Step two, define a process model for each behavior.
第二步 为每种行为定义一个过程模型
A process model is a mathematical description of object motion for behavior.
行为对应的过程模型就是用数学方式把行为相关的物体移动描述出来
It is a function which can be used to compute the state of
它是一个函数 可以用来计算一段时间结束后的物体状态
the object at time t_plus_1 from the state at
从时间 t 开始到 t+1 结束
time t. The process model must
过程模型必定会涉及到一些不确定性
incorporate some uncertainty which represents how much we trust our model.
不确定性体现出在多大程度上我们信任我们的模型
In our intersection example,
在我们的交叉路口例子里
the left turn process model would produce an uncertain future state located roughly here.
左转过程模型将产生一个不确定的未来状态 大概定位在这里
The going straight process model would produce an uncertain future state located roughly
直行过程模型也将产生一个不确定的未来状态 大概位置在这里
here and the right turn process model would
而右转弯过程模型同样
produce an uncertain future state located roughly here.
会产生不确定未来状态 大概会在这里
If you keep running the process models your uncertainty will increase.
如果你持续运行过程模型 不确定性将增加
Once we have a process model for each behavior we can go to the next step,
一旦我们为每种行为都定义了过程模型 我们便可以做下一步工作
step three, which is to use
第三步 使用过程模型
the process models to compute the probability of each behavior.
来计算每种行为的几率大小
This is done by taking the observed state of the object at time t_minus_1,
具体计算过程需要先获取时间点 t-1 上的目标状态观察值
running the process models to compute the expected state of the object at time t.
然后运行过程模型来计算得出目标在时间点 t 的预期状态
Then we compare the observed state of the object at
然后我们将在时间点 t 的物体实际观测状态
time t with what our process models predicted.
与过程模型之前的预测状态进行比较
And we use a multimodal estimation algorithm to derive the probability of each maneuver.
我们使用一个多模估量算法来获得每种可能动作的几率
The purpose of these algorithms is to maintain some belief about
这些算法的目的是
how likely it is that the driver intends to perform each behavior.
维护一些有关司机多大可能去做每种操作的预期
We'll go into more detail later.
相关内容我们后面会详细讲解
But in this case the probability of going straight
但是 就上面这个例子而言
or turning left would be higher than the probability of turning right.
直行和左转概率高于右转的概率
The fourth and final step is to predict a trajectory for each behavior.
第四步 也是最后一步 是为每种行为预测一个轨迹
This is done easily by iterating on
这很容易做到 在过程模型上进行迭代操作就可以
the process models until the prediction horizon is reached.
我们在时间上不断迭代 直到达到预测时间段的结束点
In the following videos,
我们使用过程模型来模型化行为 在后面的视频中
we talk more about the process models we use to model behaviors and then
我们会讲到更多有关过程模型的东西
discuss one version of
然后我们会讨论多模估量算法的一种版本
multimodal estimation algorithm that can be used to maintain beliefs.
多模估量算法用来维护多个预期